<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Diplomax - PrimeTime Learning]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-27T22:17:49-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[PrimeTime Learning]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIPLOMAX ADVANTAGE — the PrimeTime Learning GUARANTEE]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/diplomax-advantage-the-primetime-learning-guarantee/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-27T21:56:09-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/diplomax-advantage-the-primetime-learning-guarantee</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/images/gurantee.jpg" title="&#34;Gurantee&#34;" alt="&#34;Gurantee&#34;"></p>

<p>PrimeTime Learning has offered over 36,000 <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> review classes since 1995 in English 30, Math 30-1 and Math 30-2, Biology 30, Chemistry 30, Physics 30, Science 30, and Social Studies 30-1.  Highly qualified instructors have helped students who have taken <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> review classes raise their diploma mark anywhere from 5-20% over their term mark!  Not only is the student satisfaction rate at 94%, but <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> offers you the Prime Time Leaning Guarantee.</p>

<p>The PrimeTime Learning Guarantee assures you of the following.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Value</strong>  – When you enroll in <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> you receive a fully targeted review, practical test writing strategies, and a comprehensive Study Notes package for that subject.</li>
<li><strong>Flexibility</strong> – When you enroll in <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> and cannot attend all scheduled classes, or if you find you need more help in the same course, you can access subsequent session classes in the same course at no additional cost.</li>
<li><strong>Satisfaction</strong> – If you have previously taken <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> and decide to rewrite that diploma exam, you can take the same course again for free.</li>
</ul>


<p>Check out the <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> January schedule on the web site www.primetimelearning.ca and get immediate access to your complimentary Study Notes package when you complete your registration.</p>

<p>If you are serious about your success on the diploma exams – <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> is here to help you succeed!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diplomax Is Going Social]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/diplomax-is-going-social/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-20T17:23:21-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/diplomax-is-going-social</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/images/Social-media-for-public-relations1.jpg" title="Social Media" alt="Social Media" /></p>

<p>Thinking about post-secondary studies?  Trying to qualify for a quota faculty?  Looking at applying for a scholarship?  Worrying about getting your high school diploma? You need to check out <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> – your premium choice in diploma exam prep!</p>

<p>Follow <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/GetDiplomax">Facebook</a> and on <a href="https://twitter.com/GetDiplomax">Twitter</a> to get up-to-date information on <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> review classes.</p>

<p>Stay tuned to social media to get:</p>

<ul>
<li>tips and strategies on how to maximize your performance on the diploma exams</li>
<li>comprehensive Study Notes package for each course – delivered electronically to your home at the time of online registration</li>
<li>practice questions and complete solutions for Math30-1 and 30-2, Biology 30, Chemistry 30 , Physics 30, Science 30, English 30-1, and Social Studies 30-1</li>
<li>techniques for dealing with exam anxiety</li>
<li>practical test writing strategies – including calculator ‘tricks’</li>
<li>strategies for answering multiple choice questions</li>
<li>tips for writing strong thesis statements, essays, and personal responses</li>
<li>comprehension clues to decode meaning</li>
<li>effective study tips</li>
<li>how to prepare for an exam; how to write an exam</li>
<li>PrimeTime Learning Guarantee for <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> review classes</li>
</ul>


<p>If you are serious about your success on the diploma exams – <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> is here to help you succeed!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
