<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Diploma | Diplomax - PrimeTime Learning]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/blog/categories/diploma/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-13T18:00:51-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[PrimeTime Learning]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIPLOMAX Prep Gives Students Leg Up for Alberta Diploma Exams]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/diplomax-prep-gives-students-leg-up-for-alberta-diploma-exams/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-13T17:48:34-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/diplomax-prep-gives-students-leg-up-for-alberta-diploma-exams</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/graduation.jpg" title="&ldquo;Graduation&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>High-stakes diploma exams in January and June are always a challenge for grade 12 students.   These provincial exams count for <em>50% of a student’s final grade with the other 50% coming from school-based assessments</em>.</p>

<p>For a variety of reasons, it is becoming more and more common for students to seek assistance beyond the classroom in preparing for the diploma exams.  Entrance requirements for many post-secondary institutions have increased over the years so students need better grades to gain admittance.  The competition is extremely keen for faculties that have quotas and only take the top echelon of applicants.  Then there are the numerous scholarships available for the students who have the top grades!</p>

<p>Teachers work very diligently to get through the extensive, mandated curriculum but often find little time left in the semester for completing a review of the course content.  Students are now looking to external sources for the comprehensive review that will give them the “edge” they need to boost their diploma mark – and open the doors to the future they are seeking.</p>

<p><a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> exam prep classes provide students with what they are looking for in preparing for the high-stake, provincial diploma exams.  The focused 16-hour review classes in <strong>English 30-1, Social Studies 30-1, Biology 30, Chemistry 30, Math 30-1, Math 30-2, Physics 30 and Science 30</strong> are offered on Friday, Saturday, and Sunday over several weekends in January and June at the University of Alberta campus in Edmonton.</p>

<p>As soon as students complete their <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> registration they have immediate access to a comprehensive Study Notes package which they use to support their home study program.  In addition to the Study Notes package, students are provided with tips and strategies for writing exams, suggestions for handling exam anxiety, calculator tricks, and effective study hints.</p>

<p>More detailed information about <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> exam prep classes and the course schedule are available on the web site <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">www.primetimelearning.ca</a>  If you are still uncertain about what <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> can do to help you, read the student evaluation comments!  Every student completes an evaluation at the end of each <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> class.  Currently the satisfaction rate is 94%.</p>

<p>If you are serious about your success on the diploma exams – <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> is here to help you succeed!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
