<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Chemistry 30 | Diplomax - PrimeTime Learning]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/blog/categories/chemistry-30/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-01T18:23:11-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[PrimeTime Learning]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chemistry 30 - Sample Question and Solution #5]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/chemistry-30-sample-question-and-solution-number-5/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-01T10:10:34-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/chemistry-30-sample-question-and-solution-number-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/A6-6.png" title="&ldquo;Sample Question and Solution&rdquo;" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/A7-7.png" title="&ldquo;Sample Question and Solution&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>Are you looking for more sample questions? Like our <a href="https://www.facebook.com/GetDiplomax">Facebook</a> page or follow us on <a href="https://twitter.com/GetDiplomax">Twitter</a>. We will be posting more.</p>

<p>If you are serious about your success on the diploma exams – <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> is here to help you succeed!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chemistry 30 - Sample Question and Solution #4]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/chemistry-30-sample-question-and-solution-number-4/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-31T11:31:55-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/chemistry-30-sample-question-and-solution-number-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/A4-4.png" title="&ldquo;Sample Question and Solution&rdquo;" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/A5-5.png" title="&ldquo;Sample Question and Solution&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>Are you looking for more sample questions? Like our <a href="https://www.facebook.com/GetDiplomax">Facebook</a> page or follow us on <a href="https://twitter.com/GetDiplomax">Twitter</a>. We will be posting more.</p>

<p>If you are serious about your success on the diploma exams – <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> is here to help you succeed!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Test Writing Tips: Part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/test-writing-tips-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-06T13:33:10-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/test-writing-tips-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/exam_time2.png" title="&ldquo;Exam Time&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>Here are the “Last Five” of the Top Ten Test Writing Tips that may help you to write a stronger exam!</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Start with a question for which you know the answer</em>.  You do not have to start at the beginning of the test.  Knowing the answer to the first question you try builds your confidence and sets a positive tone for the rest of the exam.</li>
<li><em>Look for clues and information in one part of the test that helps you to answer questions in another part</em>.  Useful information is often included in diagrams, charts, graphs, photos, and source information such as the year a photo was taken or where the author lived.  Pictures, charts, graphs, and diagrams may provide a context for the question you are expected to answer.</li>
<li><em>Answer every question even if you have to guess</em>.  Leaving a question blank is guaranteed to earn you zero marks.  An educated guess in a multiple choice question gives you an opportunity to ‘luck out’.</li>
<li><em>Read over all of your answers before you hand in your test</em>.  You want to be sure you’ve answered all the questions, that your response satisfies what was asked, and that your calculations are accurate.  Where necessary include the units of measurement.</li>
<li>  <em>Finish your answers to written response or essay questions in point form if you are running out of time</em>.  This shows the marker that you have understood the question and have an organized and thoughtful response – just not enough time for complete sentences.</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="right" src="/images/exam_time.jpg" title="&ldquo;Exam Time&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>When writing an exam, there is no substitute for knowing your course material really well but you can bolster your performance by staying in the exam room for the entire amount of time and reviewing your answers.  Take a short ‘mental break’ by rolling your head from side to side and/or shrugging your shoulders.  In thinking about the overall test or reviewing specific questions, you may remember additional information to add to some of your written responses or help you with the multiple choice questions.</p>

<p>If you are serious about your success on the diploma exams – <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> is here to help you succeed!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Test Writing Tips: Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/test-writing-tips-series-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-27T22:21:31-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/test-writing-tips-series-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/test-writing-part1.jpg" title="&ldquo;Test writing tips&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>There are two components to doing well on an exam.<br/>
   <strong>One</strong> – you need to know your material. <br/> <strong>Two</strong> – you need to know <em>how</em> to write the test.  Knowing how to write the test gives you the best opportunity to demonstrate your knowledge and understanding of the course content.</p>

<p>Here are tips that may help you write a better exam.</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Start your exam by taking a few deep breaths to calm yourself</em>.  If you are feeling anxious, use positive self-talk such as, ‘I can do this’, ‘I’m ready for this’, or ‘This is going to be my best test result’.</li>
<li><em>Immediately write down any information that you do not want to forget</em>.  For example, on a math exam, write down the formulas you may need to know and use for the exam before you begin to look at the exam instructions and questions.</li>
<li><em>Look over the entire test paper or booklet to see what type(s) of and how many questions there are in total</em>.  This gives you an overview of the specific content and concepts that are being assessed, the value or number of marks for each question, and the question format(s) to which you need to respond.</li>
<li><em>Budget your time for each section of the exam before you begin answering any part of the test</em>.  You do not want to spend a lot of time on a portion of the exam that is worth only a small percentage of the total number of marks.</li>
<li><em>Read all of the instructions carefully before you begin answering any questions</em>.  It is important that you know what you are expected to do and what specifically is required in your response.</li>
</ul>


<p>Check out the blog next week for second part of this series!</p>

<p>If you are serious about your success on the diploma exams – <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> is here to help you succeed!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Study Schedules – Long-term, Short-term, and PANIC!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/study-schedules/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-20T19:18:47-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/study-schedules</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/grades.jpg" title="&ldquo;Girls with grades&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>Have you ever read the story of <em>The Hare and the Tortoise?</em>  It is a delightful children’s story of a race between two animal friends who each are confident of their ability to win a race.  The Hare sets off to a speedy start and covers a significant amount of territory before deciding he has enough of a head start on the Tortoise that he can stop for a rest.  He settles under a shady tree and enjoys a nap, confident that he can sprint to the finish line well before the Tortoise can catch up to him.</p>

<p>The Tortoise leaves the start line slowly plodding along the race path.  Though not a flashy racer, he keeps a steady pace and remains focused on getting to the finish line.  He passes the sleeping Hare and soon sees the finish line looming in the distance.  As the Tortoise is within steps of crossing the finish line and winning the race, the Hare wakes up.  He realizes he needs to make a spirited sprint to overtake the Tortoise.  Unfortunately, the Hare’s panicked dash for the finish line is “too little too late”.  The Tortoise, although a long shot, wins the race and the brazen, confident Hare is left humiliated and searching for an explanation for his loss.</p>

<p>There are many analogies that can be drawn between the race strategies of the story characters and long-term, short-term, and panic study schedules.</p>

<p><strong>Long-term Study Schedules</strong> generally are implemented well in advance of exam time and require you to set aside regular study time on an on-going basis.  Like the Tortoise a slow and steady approach helps to win the race.  The advantage of a long-term study schedule is that once you establish your study routine, it is quite easy to maintain – and shorter, regular periods of study give you the most benefit!</p>

<p><strong>Short-term Study Schedules</strong> are often implemented several days or weeks before an exam and require you to prioritize the time you spend on each topic or concept.  It may be difficult to find a “starting point”.  Do you focus on the things that are most important in the subject or on the concepts that are most challenging to you? Like the Hare, your focus may change before the end of the race.  You may skim over content that you feel you have a firm understanding of in favor of focusing on topics that feel less confident about.  Your focus may not be as consistent or as strong as it needs to be for the duration of your study or exam preparation time. The advantage of a short-term study schedule is that you gain a sense of confidence as you “check off” the topics and concepts you feel confident about.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/panic.jpeg" title="&ldquo;Panic&rdquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>Panic Study Schedules</strong> usually happen “the night before” the exam – when you realize that you do not have enough time to adequately prepare for your exam.  Although this study schedule requires the least amount of time commitment, it rarely allows you to achieve your potential.  Like the Hare, leaving too much to the end makes it impossible to finish what needs to be done.  However, any effort is better than doing nothing.</p>

<p>To achieve the grades you want requires effort on your part.  A long-term study schedule gives you the best chance for success.  A short-term study schedule may work well in a course where you have a strong understanding of the concepts.  A Panic Study Schedule is better than not studying at all but may not help you to achieve your course goals over the semester or school year.</p>

<p>Does your study strategy resemble the race strategy of the Hare or the Tortoise?</p>

<p>If you are serious about your success on the diploma exams – <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> is here to help you succeed!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
