<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Diplomax | Diplomax - PrimeTime Learning]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/blog/categories/diplomax/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-27T22:31:37-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[PrimeTime Learning]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Test Writing Tips Series: Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/test-writing-tips-series-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-27T22:21:31-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/test-writing-tips-series-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/test-writing-part1.jpg" title="&ldquo;Test writing tips&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>There are two components to doing well on an exam.<br/>
   <strong>One</strong> – you need to know your material. <br/> <strong>Two</strong> – you need to know <em>how</em> to write the test.  Knowing how to write the test gives you the best opportunity to demonstrate your knowledge and understanding of the course content.</p>

<p>Here are tips that may help you write a better exam.</p>

<ul>
<li>Start your exam by taking a few deep breaths to calm yourself.  If you are feeling anxious, use positive self-talk such as, ‘I can do this’, ‘I’m ready for this’, or ‘This is going to be my best test result’.</li>
<li>Immediately write down any information that you do not want to forget.  For example, on a math exam, write down the formulas you may need to know and use for the exam before you begin to look at the exam instructions and questions.</li>
<li>Look over the entire test paper or booklet to see what type(s) of and how many questions there are in total.  This gives you an overview of the specific content and concepts that are being assessed, the value or number of marks for each question, and the question format(s) to which you need to respond.</li>
<li>Budget your time for each section of the exam before you begin answering any part of the test.  You do not want to spend a lot of time on a portion of the exam that is worth only a small percentage of the total number of marks.</li>
<li>Read all of the instructions carefully before you begin answering any questions.  It is important that you know what you are expected to do and what specifically is required in your response.</li>
</ul>


<p>Check out the blog next time for second part of this series!</p>

<p>If you are serious about your success on the diploma exams – <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> is here to help you succeed!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Study Schedules – Long-term, Short-term, and PANIC!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/study-schedules/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-20T19:18:47-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/study-schedules</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/grades.jpg" title="&ldquo;Girls with grades&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>Have you ever read the story of <em>The Hare and the Tortoise?</em>  It is a delightful children’s story of a race between two animal friends who each are confident of their ability to win a race.  The Hare sets off to a speedy start and covers a significant amount of territory before deciding he has enough of a head start on the Tortoise that he can stop for a rest.  He settles under a shady tree and enjoys a nap, confident that he can sprint to the finish line well before the Tortoise can catch up to him.</p>

<p>The Tortoise leaves the start line slowly plodding along the race path.  Though not a flashy racer, he keeps a steady pace and remains focused on getting to the finish line.  He passes the sleeping Hare and soon sees the finish line looming in the distance.  As the Tortoise is within steps of crossing the finish line and winning the race, the Hare wakes up.  He realizes he needs to make a spirited sprint to overtake the Tortoise.  Unfortunately, the Hare’s panicked dash for the finish line is “too little too late”.  The Tortoise, although a long shot, wins the race and the brazen, confident Hare is left humiliated and searching for an explanation for his loss.</p>

<p>There are many analogies that can be drawn between the race strategies of the story characters and long-term, short-term, and panic study schedules.</p>

<p><strong>Long-term Study Schedules</strong> generally are implemented well in advance of exam time and require you to set aside regular study time on an on-going basis.  Like the Tortoise a slow and steady approach helps to win the race.  The advantage of a long-term study schedule is that once you establish your study routine, it is quite easy to maintain – and shorter, regular periods of study give you the most benefit!</p>

<p><strong>Short-term Study Schedules</strong> are often implemented several days or weeks before an exam and require you to prioritize the time you spend on each topic or concept.  It may be difficult to find a “starting point”.  Do you focus on the things that are most important in the subject or on the concepts that are most challenging to you? Like the Hare, your focus may change before the end of the race.  You may skim over content that you feel you have a firm understanding of in favor of focusing on topics that feel less confident about.  Your focus may not be as consistent or as strong as it needs to be for the duration of your study or exam preparation time. The advantage of a short-term study schedule is that you gain a sense of confidence as you “check off” the topics and concepts you feel confident about.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/panic.jpeg" title="&ldquo;Panic&rdquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>Panic Study Schedules</strong> usually happen “the night before” the exam – when you realize that you do not have enough time to adequately prepare for your exam.  Although this study schedule requires the least amount of time commitment, it rarely allows you to achieve your potential.  Like the Hare, leaving too much to the end makes it impossible to finish what needs to be done.  However, any effort is better than doing nothing.</p>

<p>To achieve the grades you want requires effort on your part.  A long-term study schedule gives you the best chance for success.  A short-term study schedule may work well in a course where you have a strong understanding of the concepts.  A Panic Study Schedule is better than not studying at all but may not help you to achieve your course goals over the semester or school year.</p>

<p>Does your study strategy resemble the race strategy of the Hare or the Tortoise?</p>

<p>If you are serious about your success on the diploma exams – <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> is here to help you succeed!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIPLOMAX Prep Gives Students Leg Up for Alberta Diploma Exams]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/diplomax-prep-gives-students-leg-up-for-alberta-diploma-exams/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-13T17:48:34-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/diplomax-prep-gives-students-leg-up-for-alberta-diploma-exams</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/graduation.jpg" title="&ldquo;Graduation&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>High-stakes diploma exams in January and June are always a challenge for grade 12 students.   These provincial exams count for <em>50% of a student’s final grade with the other 50% coming from school-based assessments</em>.</p>

<p>For a variety of reasons, it is becoming more and more common for students to seek assistance beyond the classroom in preparing for the diploma exams.  Entrance requirements for many post-secondary institutions have increased over the years so students need better grades to gain admittance.  The competition is extremely keen for faculties that have quotas and only take the top echelon of applicants.  Then there are the numerous scholarships available for the students who have the top grades!</p>

<p>Teachers work very diligently to get through the extensive, mandated curriculum but often find little time left in the semester for completing a review of the course content.  Students are now looking to external sources for the comprehensive review that will give them the “edge” they need to boost their diploma mark – and open the doors to the future they are seeking.</p>

<p><a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> exam prep classes provide students with what they are looking for in preparing for the high-stake, provincial diploma exams.  The focused 16-hour review classes in <strong>English 30-1, Social Studies 30-1, Biology 30, Chemistry 30, Math 30-1, Math 30-2, Physics 30 and Science 30</strong> are offered on Friday, Saturday, and Sunday over several weekends in January and June at the University of Alberta campus in Edmonton.</p>

<p>As soon as students complete their <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> registration they have immediate access to a comprehensive Study Notes package which they use to support their home study program.  In addition to the Study Notes package, students are provided with tips and strategies for writing exams, suggestions for handling exam anxiety, calculator tricks, and effective study hints.</p>

<p>More detailed information about <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> exam prep classes and the course schedule are available on the web site <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">www.primetimelearning.ca</a>  If you are still uncertain about what <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> can do to help you, read the student evaluation comments!  Every student completes an evaluation at the end of each <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> class.  Currently the satisfaction rate is 94%.</p>

<p>If you are serious about your success on the diploma exams – <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> is here to help you succeed!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIPLOMAX’S ELECTRONIC STUDY NOTES – PROVIDES SEMESTER SUPPORT]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/diplomaxs-electronic-study-notes-provides-semester-support/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-04T18:39:52-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/diplomaxs-electronic-study-notes-provides-semester-support</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/notes2.png" title="&ldquo;Notes&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>Complete your on-line <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> registration for the January classes at <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">www.primetimeleaning.ca</a>  and get your electronic Study Notes package IMMEDIATELY!!</p>

<p>Each student registered in a <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> review class receives a complimentary copy of the Study Notes package for that course.  Once you complete your registration, you can download the Study Notes package to your personal device or print your own copy.  The Study Notes package is approximately 150 pages of notes, tips, practice questions, reminders, etc.  You can use the Study Notes package to support your independent studying at home, to prepare for class quizzes, unit tests, homework assignments, and written assignments.</p>

<p>Sample questions, with step-by-step instructions for solving subject-specific problems are part of the electronic Study Notes package.  Download or print a single copy of the Study Notes for your personal use at home.  The earlier you register online – the longer you will have access to the Study Notes to assist you in your home study!</p>

<p>The website <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">www.primetimelearning.ca</a>  is active and accepting registrations for all subjects.  Space is limited – guarantee yourself a spot by registering NOW!</p>

<p>If you are serious about your success on the diploma exams – <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> is here to help you succeed!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIPLOMAX ADVANTAGE — the PrimeTime Learning GUARANTEE]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/diplomax-advantage-the-primetime-learning-guarantee/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-27T21:56:09-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.primetimelearning.ca/diplomax-advantage-the-primetime-learning-guarantee</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/gurantee.jpg" title="&ldquo;Gurantee&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>PrimeTime Learning has offered over 36,000 <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> review classes since 1995 in <strong>English 30, Math 30-1 and Math 30-2, Biology 30, Chemistry 30, Physics 30, Science 30, and Social Studies 30-1</strong>.  Highly qualified instructors have helped students who have taken <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> review classes raise their diploma mark anywhere from <em>5-20% over their term mark</em>!  Not only is the student satisfaction rate at 94%, but <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> offers you the Prime Time Leaning Guarantee.</p>

<p>The PrimeTime Learning Guarantee assures you of the following.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Value</strong>  – When you enroll in <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> you receive a fully targeted review, practical test writing strategies, and a comprehensive Study Notes package for that subject.</li>
<li><strong>Flexibility</strong> – When you enroll in <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> and cannot attend all scheduled classes, or if you find you need more help in the same course, you can access subsequent session classes in the same course at no additional cost.</li>
<li><strong>Satisfaction</strong> – If you have previously taken <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> and decide to rewrite that diploma exam, you can take the same course again for free.</li>
</ul>


<p>Check out the <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> January schedule on the web site <a href="http://www.primetimelearning.ca">www.primetimelearning.ca</a> and get immediate access to your complimentary Study Notes package when you complete your registration.</p>

<p>If you are serious about your success on the diploma exams – <a href="http://primetimelearning.ca/">DIPLOMAX</a> is here to help you succeed!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
